The Inspector panel in Unity
Unity のインスペクタパネルは
is a panel for adjusting
あらゆるオブジェクト、
settings for any object,
アセットおよびエディタの設定を
asset and editor preference.
調整するパネルです。
For objects, the inspector begins with a title,
オブジェクトごとに、インスペクタはタイトルがあり、
a check box for you to check if the
ゲームの中でオブジェクト状態を Static にするための
state of the object will remain static in the game.
チェックボックスがあります。
This means it's a valid candidate for
すなわち、ライトマッピングおよびナビメッシュ ベーキングの場合に
light mapping and navigation mesh baking.
チェックするか検討する有効化な候補となります。
And then the tag and layer drop-downs.
次にタグおよびレイヤーのドロップダウンボックスです。
Tags allow you to assign a tag to
タグによりひとつ以上のオブジェクトに
one or many objects in order to address them via code.
タグを割り当ててコードの中でみつけることが出来ます。
Whilst layers allow you to group objects
レイヤーによりオブジェクトのグループが出来て、
and apply certain rules to these layers
これらのレイヤーに特定のルールを定めることが出来ます。
such as lighting or collision rules.
例えばライティングや衝突に関するルールです。
After these elements the inspector then lists
これらの要素の後に、インスペクタでは
the components attached to an object.
オブジェクトにアタッチされたコンポーネントをリストにしています。
Beginning with the transform,
最初は Transform、
the default position, rotation and scale
すなわちオブジェクトの位置、回転、スケール
of your object.
です。
On any component the inspector allows
インスペクタの任意のコンポーネントにおいて
you to adjust fields in various ways.
様々な方法でフィールドの調整が出来ます。
You can drag over the values,
値の上をドラッグしたり、
you can click and retype,
クリックして、再入力したり、
or your can choose to reset the values using
あるいは値をリセットするために
the cog icon to the right of the component.
コンポーネントの右側にある歯車アイコンを使用することが出来ます。
In addition to the cog there is also a link
この歯車アイコンに加えて、
to the reference material on the component
コンポーネントのリファレンスドキュメントへのリンクがあり、
and you can get to this by clicking the
青い本のアイコンをクリックすることで
blue book icon, and this will open the
そのコンポーネントの
documentation page on this component.
ドキュメントのページが開きます。
A context sensitive panel, the inspector changes
コンテキストにより変化するパネルであるため、インスペクタは
to whatever you have selected,
選択したものによって変化します。
meaning that you can adjust any object
つまり任意のオブジェクトを調整して
and immediately dive in to settings and back.
ただちに設定を行き来することが出来ます。
Because Unity makes use of dragging and dropping to assign values
Unity はドラッグ＆ドロップにより値を割り当てることに対応しているため
sometimes you may click on items
アイテムをクリックすることによって
that take you to their settings,
自分で適用することを意図しなかった
rather than the one you wish to apply them to.
設定に入ってしまうことがあります。
And for this reason you can lock the inspector
この理由によりインスペクタのロックをすることが出来て、
in order to work with a particular item
これにより特定のアイテムでのみ作業して
and then unlock once you are done assigning settings.
作業が割り当てが終わった後にロックを外すことが出来ます。
For example on this game object I have a script component
例えばこのゲームオブジェクトでは Script コンポーネントに
to which I must assign an array of textures.
テクスチャの配列を割り当てる必要がある場合があります。
But when I select my first texture I want the inspector
しかし、最初のテクスチャを選択したとき、ゲームオブジェクトに
to remain on my game object,
テクスチャの設定を表示するのではなく
rather than showing the texture's settings.
インスペクタを残したい場合があります。
I could simply hold down the mouse
マウスボタンを押したままにするか
or I can simply select the object
単にオブジェクトを選択して
and click on the lock at the top of the inspector.
インスペクタの最上部にあるロックをクリックすることが出来ます。
This way when I select one or many textures
この方法により、ひとつ以上のテクスチャを選択したとき
I can then drag and drop without the inspector changing focus.
インスペクタでフォーカスが変更することなくドラッグ＆ドロップすることが出来ます。
Once I am done with this I simply click the lock again
これが完了した後は、ロックを再びクリックして
and I can then select anything that I need to.
そして必要なものを選択することが出来ます。
The inspector also offers a way of finding assets used on objects.
インスペクタはオブジェクトで使用されるアセットをみつける方法を提供します。
For example materials.
例えばマテリアルなどです。
When clicking on an asset used within a renderer
レンダラの中で使用されているアセットをクリックする場合、
you can see that asset highlighted inside the project panel.
プロジェクトパネルの中でハイライトされているアセットをみることが出来ます。」
It does this by highlighting with a yellow outline.
黄色いアウトラインを表示するうことでハイライトします。
This helps you easily find the assets that your
これによりゲームオブジェクトが依存するアセットを
game objects depend upon.
容易にみつけることが出来ます。
In this example we can see an object that has a material
このサンプルではレンダラにアサインされているマテリアルをもつ
assigned to it's renderer.
オブジェクトが表示されています。
This particular material is then previewed
この特定のマテリアルは
at the bottom of the inspector
インスペクタの最下部でプレビューされて、
and I can adjust that material directly from here.
マテリアルを直接ここから調整することが出来ます。
However, the other two objects that I don't have selected
しかし、他の二つの選択していないオブジェクトは
also use this material, so I must bare in mind that
このマテリアルをまた使用するため、
the actual material I am adjusting
調整している実際のマテリアルは
is the original material asset inside the project
プロジェクトの中のオリジナルのマテリアルアセットであり、
and not a particular instance of an object
オブジェクトの特定のインスタンスではないことを覚えておくべきです。
in the same way that I can adjust the scale of this object
同様にして、このオブジェクトのスケールを調整して
without adjusting any other objects that
他のスケールの値のあるオブジェクトに影響なく
also have a scale value.
変更できます。
Components within the inspector can also be disabled
インスペクタの中のコンポーネントもまた無効化するには
by clicking the checkbox to the left of their name.
名前の左にあるチェックボックスをクリックします。
And the entire object can be disabled by clicking
そしてオブジェクト全体を無効化するには
the checkbox next to it's name
インスペクタの最上部にある、
at the top of the inspector.
名前の隣にあるチェックボックスをクリックします。
When objects are disabled in this way
このようにオブジェクトが無効化された場合
you'll notice that their name is greyed out
Hierarchy パネルの中で名前が
inside the hierarchy panel.
グレーアウトされることに気付きます。
And that's the basics of the inspector in Unity.
そして Unity におけるインスペクタの基本はこれで完了です。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)